Athens, GA, 30605

Kushajveer Singh

(706) 461-9944 kushajreal@gmail.com kushajveersingh.com

SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

Full-stack developer experienced with doing API integrations, reading documentation to add new features to an existing codebase, code review processes, CI/CD testing. Self-motivated and passionate to learn new technologies and build projects on top of it. Experienced with deploying more than 6 <u>projects</u> on Vercel/Heroku, contributing to open-source projects on <u>GitHub</u> for over 5 years, and maintaining a technical <u>blog</u> with 16 published posts.

EDUCATION

University of Georgia, Franklin College of Arts & Sciences Master of Science in Computer Science (GPA: 3.82/4.00) Athens, GA, USA Jan 2021 – Dec 2022

Punjab Engineering College (Deemed to be University)

Bachelor of Technology in Electronics and Communication Engineering (CGPA: 7.0/10.0)

Chandigarh, India Aug 2016 – Jun 2020

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- C, C++, Python, PyTorch, Git, GitHub, Circle CI, Docker, Shell Scripting, Web Scraping, Agile (Scrum), Linux
- HTML, CSS (BEM), Sass, JavaScript, TypeScript, jQuery, React, Next.js, Redux, Material UI, Stripe, Twilio, Bcrypt, OAuth, Sanity, Jest, Node.js, Express, Django, PHP, MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, REST APIs

WORK EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Developer

Athens, GA, USA

College of Agriculture and Environmental Sciences, UGA

Jul 2022 - current

- Implemented Node.js/Express parser to do real time Microsoft Access to PostgreSQL query conversion
- Brought up development and production servers, including IP whitelisting and backup configuration with periodic syncing, and migrated 18 years of data from Access to PostgreSQL database
- Automated data entry pipeline using Python/TypeScript, resulting in a reduction of time from 2 minutes per handwritten form to 25 seconds on average, by implementing autocomplete functionality for various fields
- Rewrote the entire codebase for a proprietary language, which included converting information from a 200-page manual to a *TypeScript/Next.js* application and updating the queries from *Access* to *PostgreSQL*

Graduate Teaching Assistant

Computer Science Department, UGA

Athens, GA, USA

Jan 2022 - Aug 2022

- Led weekly meetings and facilitated group discussions for the course Discrete Mathematics for Computer Science
- Held one-on-one office hours for 2 transfer students, covering the entire course in detail while covering practical
 applications of the content and mentored students on the career paths in computer science

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

Google CS Research Mentorship Program

Student

Athens, GA, USA (Remote) Sep 2022 – Dec 2022

Selected for a 12-week Google Research program among 50 candidates from across USA and Canada

Winner TechGiq CodeGladiators

Hackathon

Punjab, India May 2019 – Jul 2019

- Won the first solo place in Artificial Intelligence hackathon where 15 teams were selected from across India from a pool of about 0.6 million candidates
- Built a fully deployable and unsupervised parking space detection system using PyTorch and OpenCV
- Ability to adjust predictions based on where cars are parked over time

Third place North-Zone IndiaSkills Nationals

IT Software Solutions for Business

Chandigarh, India Sep 2018 – Nov 2018

- Built desktop application using C# and android application using Java to win third place at IndiaSkills nationals
- Both applications fetched data from a MySQL and phpMyAdmin database setup

PROJECT EXPERIENCE

YouTube Video Platform | GITHUB, DEMO

- Built fully-responsive React/Next.js/TypeScript/Material-UI web app using YouTube API and deployed on Vercel
- Implemented video section, category section, responsive channel and video cards, channel pages, video pages with ability to play videos straight from the app and see related videos

Chat Messaging App

- Built fully-responsive full-stack chat messaging application using React/TypeScript/Bcrypt/Stream Chat API
- Support for authentication, Twilio SMS notification, direct and group chats, emojis and reactions, GIF support
- Deployed React frontend on Vercel, and deployed Express is backend on Heroku

Ecommerce Website

- Built full-responsive and scalable modern ecommerce website using Next.js/TypeScript and deployed on Vercel
- Used Next.js as backend endpoint, stripe for managing payments, shipping rates and entire checkout process
- Manage entire content of website using Sanity, to change details of products or add new products on the go

Music Player and Discovery App

- Built fully-responsive modern music player app using React/Tailwind CSS/TypeScript/Redux/Shazam API
- Choose genre and view top songs, see top charts and artists for the country or worldwide
- Music player with controls to go to next/previous song, repeat, shuffle, fast forward, adjust volume
- Fully functional search and pages to explore most popular songs in the country, using IP Geolocation API
- View song's lyrics and official video, related songs, and other songs by the artist

Video Sharing Social Media App

- Built fully-responsive full-stack video sharing social media app using React/Next.js/TypeScript/Tailwind CSS/ Zustand/Sanity
- Google auth to register and login user, ability to upload, publish, share, comment on and like the videos
- Advanced search functionalities, filter by categories, profile pages, and see suggested accounts

Sort Visualizer

- Built React/TypeScript/Redux/Material-UI web app for visualizing sorting algorithms and deployed on Vercel
- Implemented over 30 sorting algorithms, and can view up to 9 algorithms in parallel
- Can adjust animation speed, pause, restart, and generate 4 types of random arrays

Group Video Chat

- Built group video chat app using JavaScript/Agora, and deployed the backend on Heroku and frontend on Vercel
- Conference chat with multiple people at same time, screen share, private/group messaging, admin controls, polls
- Worked with an enterprise scale codebase and added features on top of it by reading documentation

JSON/YAML Graph Visualizer

- Built React/Next.js/Redux/Material-UI web app to convert JSON/YAML data into graph for improved readability
- Wrote YAML to JSON parser in TypeScript

Bookstore application

- Built full-stack bookstore application using HTML/CSS/JavaScript for frontend and Django/SQLite for backend
- Implemented user authentication with email, change/forgot password, edit profile, advanced search options, cart management, apply promotions, entire process for placing an order